Khanh Q. Ngo

(857) 600-8439 | khan.ngo@gmail.com

SUMMARY:

A highly motivated and independent IT professional with over 20 years of experience in fast paced enterprise environments in financial, insurance, tourism, and e-Commerce, experienced across Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including planning, development, testing, configuration management, and deployment, and a strong passion for automation for scalability, increased efficiency, and reduction in manual processes.

EXPERIENCES:

CVS Health (May 2020 - Present)

Digital Monitoring Architect | July 2020– Present | Woonsocket, RI

- Provide subject matter expertise (SME) in the area of monitoring and alerting
- Make recommendations to improve metrics on Digital Key Performance Indicators (KPI's) such as MTTD, MTTR, MTBF, etc
- Coordinate with the Digital Architecture team to align on core strategy and direction.

Digital Site Reliability Engineer (Contractor) | May 2020– July 2020 | Woonsocket, RI

- Monitored and continuously improve the availability and performance of infrastructure, systems, and applications
- Partnered closely with product teams, customer engagement teams, application technical teams, business analysts to identify core business/technical metrics indicative of KPIs and system health.
- Captured and analyzed data on Systems Availability, MTBF, and MTTR across all Digital channels; identify patterns and drive changes to both systems and processes to provide sustained improvements.

TJX Companies (2020)

Web Operations Engineer (Contractor) | February 2020 - April 2020 | Framingham, MA

- Supported, monitored, and maintained critical web-functionality of 24/7 e-Commerce sites
- Initiated GitFlow branching/merging strategy to improve speed, efficiency, and scalability of the build process
- Collaborated with Rackspace to review Jenkins pipeline to streamline the Continuous Integration (CI) practices
- Supported the software development life cycle and Agile development methodologies
- Leveraged Application Performance Management (APM) and web analytics tools such as Splunk, AppDynamics, Google Analytics, and Omniture / Adobe Analytics

Leisure Pass Group (2019 - 2020)

Software Application Support Engineer / Java developer | September 2019 – February 2020 | Boston, MA

- Built and Maintained Continuous Integration with CircleCI and Bamboo to build, test, and deployment
- Managed, and performed deployment of software components into lower and Production environments
- Troubleshoot compile and build failures, and facilitated resolution
- Proven ability to excel working within in 2-weeks sprint iterative agile development environment
- Acquired AWS certification and increased working knowledge with EC2, ELB, S3, and RDS
- Utilized JUnit for unit testing, IntelliJ for static analysis, and Clover for code-coverage tools for Java
- Developed React and Java code using Git with repositories in GitHub
- Heavily use SQL against MySQL and NoSQL for MongoDB to manage app and troubleshoot issues
- Implemented API test automation test automation for Postman, JMeter
- Worked to continuously identified opportunities for automation and operational efficiencies

Vestmark (2018 - 2019)

Systems Engineer (Managed Services Team) | June 2018 - September 2019 | Wakefield, MA

- Troubleshoot issues across the stack (hardware, network, applications, database, storage)
- Implemented production changes while adhering to standardized change control protocols
- Utilized APM tools to monitor, track trends, and proposed solutions to recurring issues
- Monitored and resolve any nightly MS SQL databases backups issues
- Developed automation scripts using PowerShell for internal monitoring and alerting

Liberty Mutual Insurance Group (2011 – 2018)

Software Developer | March 2017 – June 2018 | Boston, MA

- Produced clean and reusable software in fail-fast, rapid iteration, greenfield, Agile development environment
- Obtained mastery of Git source control management system for repositories hosted on GitHub and bitbucket
- Utilized Selenium 2.0 WebDriver, Jest, Enzyme, and Cucumber for functional test automation
- Created and maintained continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) process documentation
- Achieved success in transforming the renewal experience for the personal insurance market

Senior Software Systems Engineer | October 2011 – March 2017 | Boston, MA

- Designed clear, comprehensive system, technical and infrastructure solutions in the monitoring space, that supported current and future direction
- Reviewed major infrastructure designs from a monitoring perspective to ensure consistency, maintainability and flexibility with respect to overall system, technical and product architectures within a market
- Worked effectively with senior systems engineers, developers, software owners (IT and business customers), production support teams, project managers, and senior managers
- Provided 24x7 support for IBM's Websphere Application Server (WAS6.1, 7.x, 8.x), IBMIHS, Weblogic, IIS, Tomcat, Siteminder, LDAP, BigIP, Teradata, Splunk, AppDynamics, Introscope

State Street Corporation (2000 - 2011)

Application Support Engineer | September 2008 – October 2011 | Westwood, MA

- Maintained, monitored, and supported UNIX/Linux Applications and databases
- Performed Oracle Database Administration (DBA) tasks to monitor and maintain system health
- Managed the deployment of software components into QA, UAT, Pre-Prod, and Production environments

Data Center Operations Night Shift Manager | September 2004 – September 2007 | Quincy, MA

- Technical Support Manager for the night shift Open Systems support in 24x7 environment
- Lead problem management, post mortem analysis, and root cause analysis

Application Support | June 2001 - September 2004 | Boston, MA

- Provided 3rd tier support for a real-time enterprise online data delivery application in 24x7 environment
- Deployment Management responsibilities including planning, implementation, and reporting

Network Operating Center Communications Analyst | April 2000 – June 2001 | Quincy, MA

- Supported enterprise servers and applications Open Systems Environment
- Monitored system health and application functions

TRAINING:

Platform by Per Scholas (April 2019 - Aug 2019)

Java Full-Stack Web Developer Program | Cambridge, MA

Training covered exploration on how to be efficient in Agile-Scrum project methodologies using Jira. Managed databases requiring SQL and learned how to install, configure, connect, query with MariaDB. Additional topics included collections, basic I/O, JDBC, JPA, Spring MVC, and Spring Boot.

General Assembly (March 2017 – June 2017**)**

Web Development Immersive Program | Boston, MA

Full Stack Web development program focusing on ES6 JavaScript, BootStrap, JSON, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Ruby, Rails, Node, Express, Ember, React.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL, GIT, problem-solving, planning, modeling, and maintaining applications with client-API architectures.

CERTIFICATION:













